Finding Aid for the Miriam Matthews photograph collection, 1781-1989 LSC.1889
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Daily Life in Black Los Angeles and California., 1885-1980.
  - Social clubs, Greek societies, Community Organizations.
    - Stovall Foundation. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of Fairmount Terrace building (I and II), Stovall Sanatorium in Duarte, Board of Directors, an announcement for new organization to be named Outdoor Life and Health Association, and a portrait of Dr. Leonard Stovall (negative).
    - Floyd Covington, Los Angeles Urban League., 1918. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Includes photograph of Covington as a child. Later her became membership secretary of 28th Street Y.M.C.A., then industrial secretary of the Los Angeles branch of the National Urban League, and in 1931 he was appointed executive director of the branch.
    - Pasadena Women's Clubs., 1910-1916. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs of 10th Annual Convention California State Federation of Colored Women's Clubs, Pasadena; a group of unidentified club women in Pasadena.
    - Sojourner Truth Club, members and events., 1913-1964. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of founders, club houses, presidents, annual breakfast, groundbreaking ceremony, and other events.
    - Sojourner Truth Club, buildings. (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Includes photographs of Harvard Clubhouse, opened in 1954;the first clubhouse opened in 1913 on Adams Blvd.; clubhouse on Crenshaw, dedicated in 1967.
    - Phys-Art-Lit Club., 1935. (Box 26, Folder 7)
      Photographs of the group in 1935. The second oldest African American women's club in Los Angeles.
    - Margaret Murray Washington. (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Wife of prominent African American figure, Booker T. Washington. She was principal of Tuskegee Institute where she met and married him in 1892. She was elected National Federation of Afro-American Women (NFAW), and helped merge with the Colored Women's League to form the National Association of Colored Women.
    - Political Study Clubs. (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Includes photographs of Los Angeles County Negro Democratic Club and monthly meeting of Westside Republican Women's Club.
    - Avalon Community Center., 1962. (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Includes photograph of Opal Jones and Tom Bradley at Avalon Community Center.
    - Scott's Hall., 1901. (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Founded by John and Margaret Scott
    - Alpha Phi Alpha fraternity, Los Angeles., 1921. (Box 26, Folder 12)
      Includes photograph of founders of APA in 1921 and a photocopied History of the Alpha Delta Chapter of Los Angeles.
    - Wilfandel Club. (Box 26, Folder 13)
      Photographs of early members of African American women's club, founded in 1945.
    - Social Clubs, 1920s. (Box 26, Folder 14)
      Includes photographs of the Nannettes, the Utopians First Annual Ball, and the Silver Fox Annual Ball.
    - London Bridge Club., c. 1940-1950. (Box 26, Folder 15)
      Includes group photographs of members.
    - Twelve Thirty-three Bridge Club. (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Girl Friends Club. (Box 26, Folder 17)
      Includes photographs of club members at parties, including performing in a Hawaiian skit.
    - Pioneer Club and Old Pals Club. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of black pioneers to Los Angeles, at Pioneer Club and Old Pals Club events.
    - Diane Athletic Club. (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Includes negative of Dianes bicycling in Exposition Park, and photograph of Dianes at a ball.
    - Links Inc., c. 1950. (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of the presentation of checks to charities at a cotillion, and several group photograph of members.
    - Community Improvement Organizations., 1938-1950. (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs of the Pilgrim House, Eastside Settlement, Beulah Home for Colored, Aged and Infirm, National Youth Administration Works Progress Program, Phillis Wheatley Home.
    - Sacramento Clubs. (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of an unidentified Sacramento clubhouse and the Star Club's Easter Ball in 1924.
    - Golden State Council and Juveniles., 1914. (Box 27, Folder 6)
      Photograph of group in front of 8th and Towne church.
    - Group of men from unidentified club or organization, wearing ribbons. (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Group includes Frederick Roberts.
    - Negro Congress and U.S.C Negro Club. (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Includes photographs of Afro-American Congress Convention in Los Angeles (1896), National Negro Congress, and University of Southern California Negro Club.
    - Women's Social Groups and Unidentified Social Clubs. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Mixed Social Groups and Unidentified Social Clubs. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Politicians, Public Officials, Diplomats.
    - James E. Stratten, first African American to serve on Board of Education, San Francisco., 1961. (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Includes photograph of Stratten being sworn in for the school board.
    - Thomas L. Griffith, attorney, civil rights activist, and judge in the Los Angeles municipal court. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Includes individual portrait of Griffith, a photograph with his two daughters, a banquet in his honor given by the Second Baptist Church in 1968, and a photograph of his oath of office as newly elected superior court judge.
    - Black Attorneys and Judges in Los Angeles., 1912-1990. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Includes photograph of Bert McDonald, Deputy City Attorney; a group of attorneys and judges celebrating Curtis Taylor's birthday; a portrait of Hon. Bernard S. Jefferson; portrait of Judge David W. Williams; portrait of Judge Billy Mills; drawing of Honorable Mifflin W. Gibbs; various portraits of Hon. Edwin L. Jefferson; photograph of Attorney Christopher Darden's home at Lake Elsinore; Willis O. Tyler; Richard Charles O'Hara Benjamin; and attorney E. Burton Ceruti.
    - William Byron Rumford, Member of California State Assembly and legislator of Fair Housing Act (1963). (Box 28, Folder 8)
      Includes photograph of Rumford and his wife.
    - Tom Bradley, mayor of Los Angeles., 1962-1963. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Includes individual portraits of Bradley, a reception in his honor at the Pacific Town club with his wife and Charles Matthews,
    - Jesse Terry, Los Angeles Housing Authority. (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Includes photographs of Terry with her family, with the Los Angeles Housing Authority, a banquet in her honor given by the First A.M.E. Church, and a portrait of her sister Emma Lue Sayers, a musician and activist. Also includes a photographic copy of her award of service.
    - Juanita Terry, administrative assistant to Congresswoman Helen Gahagan Douglas and active member of Democratic Party. (Box 28, Folder 11)
      Includes photograph of her with Congresswoman Douglas, portrait with Beulah Terry, and group photographs with family and colleagues.
    - Hon. Walter Gordon. (Box 28, Folder 12)
      Includes individual portraits, and photographs with his family.
    - Group of politicians. (Box 28, Folder 13)
      Includes August Hawkins, Gilbert Lindsay, Tom Bradley, Billy Mills, Dollar Hide, Mervyn Dymally, and Goodwin Knight
    - Elected and Appointed Government Officials. (Box 28, Folder 14)
      Includes Ed and Augustus Hawkins, Commander Nelson, Dave Cunningham, Gilbert Lindsay, E.L. Chew, John Buggs, and Jesse Jackson.
    - Mervyn Dymally, Lieutenant Governor of California and Congressman. (Box 28, Folder 15)
      Includes individual portraits of Dymally.
    - Blanche Bruce, first non-white senator to serve a full term., 1875-1881. (Box 28, Folder 16)
      Includes portrait of Bruce, a mixed race U.S. Senator from Mississippi.
    - Ethiopia's Emperor Haile Selassie I entertained in Los Angeles., 1954. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Includes photograph of a civic luncheon at the Ambassador Hotel.
    - Chart Analyzing the Growth of Minority Group Population in Los Angeles City and County., 1940-1957. (Box 29, Folder 2)
      Includes photographic copy of this chart
    - Ralph Bunche, UCLA years., 1923-1927. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of Ralph Bunche as a young man, a copy of page from the UCLA yearbook (1927), photograph of Bunche and Charles Matthews, Bunche playing basketball at UCLA
    - Ralph Bunche, residences and family photographs. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs and negatives of Bunche's Los Angeles residences including E. 37th St., negative of Bunche with wife and daughter Joan at a reception honoring their family hosted by Charles Matthews, and photographs and negatives of several female relatives.
    - Ralph Bunche, portraits and diplomatic work. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Includes portraits of Bunche and photographs with Walter White and Rev. E. C. Estel, Bunche as a guest at the Council on World Affairs, and other U.N. officials.
    - Ralph Bunche, receiving awards. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Includes photographs of Bunche receiving the Spingarn medal at the NAACP convention in 1949, a reception at Jefferson High School in that same year, his reception of a resolution from the Los Angeles City Council in 1966.
  - Business, Professionals, and Laborers.
    - Baumann's Pharmacy. (Box 30, Folder 13)
      Includes photographs of Albert C. Baumann, his pharmacy on Central Ave., his pharmacy in New Orleans. Also includes photographs of his wife Corona White and her parents.
    - Richard B. Spikes, inventor. (Box 30, Folder 14)
      Includes photographic copy of a page from "Black Inventors of America" by McKinley Burt, Jr., explaining Spikes' invention of the "fail-safe" brake for motor vehicles.
    - C.H. Perry Furniture Store., 1904. (Box 30, Folder 15)
      Includes photograph of the store and Perry from the "Liberator" magazine in 1904.
    - Canadian Furniture Company, owned by James H. Shackleford. (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of James H. Shackleford and wife, and their furniture store on Central Ave. See box 18, folder 5, for photographs from the Shackleford family of the People's Independent Church.
    - Pharmacies and Pharmacists. (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of these businesses featured in a Western Progress 1928 issue: Washington and Central Pharmacy, Bowers Drug Store, Harris Pharmacies, Eagleson Pharmacy, Lone Star Pharmacy, Nickerson's Drug Store, Smith Drug Stores, Leon C. Clark Pharmacist, Brooks Bros. Pharmacy, and Alonzo Aljack Adams, manufacturer of proprietary medicines.
    - Funeral Homes. (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of A.J. Roberts and Sons Mortuary, the Angelus Funeral Home, the officers of the Angelus Funeral Home, a negative of the Smith and Williams Company Funeral Directors, a negative of the Conner- Johnson and Company Funeral Directors. Many are taken from a 1928 issue of "Western Progress."
    - Golden State Mutual Life Insurance offices. (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs of GSM first and second offices on Central Ave. (1925), the first office building built for GSM and its groundbreaking(1928), the main office building at Adams and Western (1948, designed by Paul R. Williams). Also includes photograph from the dedication of its home office building and murals in 1949. Photographs of murals and artists can be found at box 1, folders 14-17.
    - William Nickerson Jr., Founder and President of Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company. (Box 31, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of Nickerson Jr., his home in "Western Progress" magazine (1928), his eight children, four of his children as adults, and his family.
    - George A. Beavers Jr., founding vice president of Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company. (Box 31, Folder 6)
      Includes portraits of Beavers.
    - Norman O. Houston, founding secretary/treasurer of Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company and president from 1945 to 1970. (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Includes portraits of Houston, military, and baseball photographs. The same military photographs of Houston can be found in box 19, folders 13 and 14.
    - Leaders of Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company., 1944-1966. (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Includes photograph of Edgar J. Johnson, group photograph of Nickerson, Beavers, and Houston, the GSM officers receiving "Old Line Legal Reserve" permit from deputy insurance commissioner, and the board of directors in 1966.
    - Family Savings and Loan. (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Includes photographs of office building in 1964, founder M. Earl Grant, board of directors in 1964.
    - Broadway Federal Savings and Loan. (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Includes photographs of office building on Broadway, a board of directors meeting, and portrait of H. Claude Hudson and son in 1916. Hudson, a successful dentist, helped found the Savings and Loan in 1946.
    - Liberty Building and Loan Association, first African American financial institution in Los Angeles. (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Includes photographs of office in 1929, its officers and directors from a 1928 issue of "Western Progress", Wilbur C. Gordon, first president, and a negative of a group of officers
    - Unity Finance Company. (Box 31, Folder 12)
      Includes photograph of building from 1928 issue of "Western Progress"
    - Black Businessmen in Los Angeles. (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Includes photographs of groups of businessmen including Louis M. Blodgett, Dr. H. Claude Hudson, Norman O. Houston, M. Earl Grant, Frank A. Harvey Jr., J.B. Bass, J.H. Shackleford, Albert Baumann, and George Johnson.
    - Real Estate Companies featured in the "Liberator"., 1904. (Box 31, Folder 14)
      All photographs are taken from a 1904 issue of the "Liberator." Includes, real estate office of J.B. Loving, Francis P. Jones Company, Knox-Knox Realty Brokers, George S. Grant Company, the Walter L. Gordon Company, and negative of Washington and Lee real estate.
    - Noah D. Thompson Realty Co., 1904. (Box 31, Folder 15)
      Advertisement from the "Liberator" Jan-Feb 1904.
    - Golden West Real Estate Board., 1939. (Box 31, Folder 16)
      Includes photograph of first banquet
    - Sid Dones Real Estate, Notary, Loans. (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Includes advertisement from "Official Central Ave. District Directory" (1940), photograph from Western Progress of his Associated Loan Company, and negative of his real estate office.
    - New Age Publishing Co. (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Photograph with Los Angeles Citizen's Band playing in front.
    - "The Enterprise" newspaper office., 1904. (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Includes photograph from the "Liberator" in 1904.
    - The Pacific Defender newspaper publisher., 1928. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Includes photograph from "Western Progress" in 1928.
    - The California Eagle newspaper. (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Includes photo of John J. Neimore, founder and first editor of the "Eagle," copied from "Forty Years: Memoirs from the Pages of a Newspaper," by Charlotta Bass. Photograph of Joseph Blackburn Bass in front of the office, the office interior from the "Western Progress" in 1928, Charlotta Bass in front of the office, Charlotta Bass with Progressive Independent Party Candidate for U.S. President Henry Wallace,
    - Journalist Libby Clark with Kenneth Morris of the YMCA. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Noah D. Thompson, Associated Editor on the Daily Express and Tribune of Los Angeles. (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Includes photograph of Delilah Beasley's "Negro Trail Blazers of California"
    - Western Progress, publisher's preface., 1928. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - California newspapers outside Los Angeles. (Box 32, Folder 9)
      Includes photograph of "Monrovia Planet" office and press of Charles F. Tilgham, editor and publisher of Colored Directory of the Leading Cities of Northern California, 1916-1917.
    - Scott's Hall. (Box 32, Folder 10)
      Negative photograph of Scott's Hall, erected by John Scott.
    - The Ohio House. (Box 32, Folder 11)
      Includes photograph of exterior from "The Liberator", 1904.
    - La Vada Apartments. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - The Somerville Hotel. (Box 32, Folder 13)
      Includes photographs of hotel built by John and Vada Somerville in 1928, including the interior, exterior, and groundbreaking ceremony.
    - The Hotel Jones, first African American owned hotel in Los Angeles., c. 1900. (Box 32, Folder 14)
      Includes photographs of interior and exterior of hotel, owned by A.J. "Biscuit" Jones.
    - The Austin House. (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - The Darby Hotel, built by Charles Blodgett an African American contractor. (Box 32, Folder 16)
      Includes photograph of hotel exterior, originally owned by whites, and many years later purchased by blacks.
    - Brick building being built by black masons., c. 1904. (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Julian Hotel, owned by formerly enslaved Albert Robinson and wife., 1984. (Box 32, Folder 18)
      Includes photograph of exterior with plaque explaining hotel's history including its status as the "Southland's oldest continuously operated hotel" established in 1887
    - San Francisco hotels,., c. 1846, 1939. (Box 32, Folder 19)
      Includes drawing of Old City Hotel, 1846 (relationship to African American population unknown), San Francisco Palace Hotel black chambermaids and porters on the upper balcony of the Grand Court.
    - Eugene Walker's Tailor Shop, featured in Crisis Magazine., 1913. (Box 32, Folder 20)
      Includes photograph of shop interior from the Crisis.
    - Los Angeles Black Businesses featured in the "Liberator," 1904. (Box 32, Folder 21)
      Includes: Robert T. Boyd's Tonsorial Parlor, a blacksmith shop, a crockery store, L.A. Van and Storage Co., the Great Western Stove and Repair Co., Miss Helen Warner, stenographer, the Flint Grocery, H. Stricklin's Butcher Shop,
    - Los Angeles Black Businesses featured in "Western Progress," 1928. (Box 32, Folder 22)
      Includes: photography studios, eateries, manufacturing companies, barber shop, flower shop, laundry, millinery and clothing retail
    - Advertisements for black businesses in Los Angeles. (Box 32, Folder 23)
      Includes photographs of a shoe repair business and Acacia Photo Engraving Co., both from the Alpha Phi Alpha Souvenir program. Also includes an advertisement for Victory Market (opened in 1942) from an unidentified source.
    - Noah's Ark Cafeteria, San Mateo, California. (Box 32, Folder 24)
      Includes photographs of restaurant exterior and portraits of Noah Williams, owner.
    - Black Businesses in Los Angeles. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Includes photograph of Eddie Grice and employee in his sausage shop, aerial view of black businesses, Claude McKinney, sign painter, William Marcus, tailor, C.C. Flint, grocery store, Glover Tailoring School (also see), a rubbish hauling company, Hugh Gordon Bookshop,
    - Blodgett Motor Company and Tivoli Motors Company. (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Photographs from Western Progress issue 1928
    - Gus Thompson, stagecoach driver and livery stable owner. (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of Thompson driving his stagecoach and carriages, negative bust portrait of wife, school picture including his children, photograph of his daughter, photograph of his livery stable, and negative of Mrs. Thompson's lunch room and bakery.(See also box 1, folder 6)
    - Attendants on the H.F. Alexander Ocean Liner. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Included in group is Garner Van Grayson Jr.
    - Red Caps, Southern Pacific Railroad Company. (Box 33, Folder 5)
      Includes group of Red Caps, most identified, at Central Station
    - Mr. Offutt washing street cars at Los Angeles Car Barn. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Agricultural Workers on Lucky Baldwin's ranch., 1886. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Diamond Coal Company (white-owned) and Harvey Brothers Sand and Gravel Contractors. (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Includes photograph of Harvey family, and Benjamin Talbot as driver for white-owned Diamond Coal Company.
    - Farming and Ranching in California. (Box 33, Folder 9)
      Includes photograph of cotton picker on machinery in 1968, a herd of cattle from the town of Allensworth, and a negative of the Dunbar ranch
    - Driver for Pacific Creamery using cow to pull "Lily Cream" Wagon., c. 1905. (Box 33, Folder 10)
      Photograph of black driver for white company
    - Janitors under L.G. Robinson. (Box 33, Folder 11)
      Includes L.G. Robinson with his janitorial staff for the Hall of the Records, and with Los Angeles County janitors for which he was supervisor.
    - Dr. Ruth Temple, first black woman in California to graduate from medical school and to practice medicine. (Box 33, Folder 12)
      Includes individual portraits of Temple. For more see box 15, folder 8.
    - Dr. A.C. Garrott, first African American dentist in Los Angeles County. (Box 33, Folder 13)
      Includes photographs of home in Glendale, family photographs, individual portraits, his children with playmates, photographs of his business, photographs of other relatives, and photographs of downtown Los Angeles taken by Dr. Garrott
    - Dr. Monroe Majors, first black physician to practice west of the Rockies. (Box 33, Folder 14)
      Includes individual portraits, a photographic copy of his diploma for medical school, photograph with his wife and daughter, photograph with attorney Richard Charles O'Hara Benjamin.
    - Dr. Thomas Nelson, first black man to receive medical degree from Stanford University. (Box 33, Folder 15)
      Includes portraits of Nelson and photographs of his office.
    - Professor E.L. Chew. (Box 33, Folder 16)
      Individual portrait.
    - Construction Gang in Sacramento. (Box 33, Folder 17)
      Photograph includes David Bennett Hundley, cement worker and father Clarissa Hundley Wildy (see box 15, folder 14).
    - Louis Blodgett, successful contractor. (Box 33, Folder 18)
      Includes photograph of Blodgett eating. For photographs of his wife of the Allensworth family see box 5, folder 6.
    - Dr. T.P. Moore, physician?. (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Dr. George Pryce, pharmacist. (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Dr. Wilbur Gordon, physician. (Box 34, Folder 1)
      See also box 31, folder 11.
    - Dr. Leroy Weekes. (Box 34, Folder 2)
      See also box 16, folder
    - Physicians, Dentists, Pharmacists and the Dunbar Hospital., 1928. (Box 34, Folder 3)
      From Western Progress, 1928.
    - Dr. G.D. Taylor, physician. (Box 34, Folder 4)
      Photograph from the Liberator (1904), office of Dr. G.D. Taylor.
    - Dr. James Leggett, wife Cornelia, and daughter., c. 1901. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Dr. Charles A. Jackson M.D. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Dr. Charles Dent, second black intern at Los Angeles General Hospital. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Dr. George Bernard Key. (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Photograph in front of house.
    - African American male doctors, last names A through E. (Box 34, Folder 9)
      Includes portraits of Drs. Adrien, Arthurton, Ball, Beasley, Booker, Carr, Cobbs, Cooley, Daily, Davis, Delahoussaye, DeVaughn, Diggs, and Everett.
    - African American male doctors, last names F through O. (Box 34, Folder 10)
      Includes portraits of Drs. Foster, Frederick, Gordon, Hamilton, Harwell, Hepson, Irving, King, LaVigne, Liddell, Malloney, Marmillion, Morgan, Nailor, Nelson, and Outlaw.
    - African American male doctors, last names R through W. (Box 34, Folder 11)
      Includes portraits of Drs. Robinson, Rodgers, Ross, Scales, Smitherman, Stovall, Taylor, Terrell, Tucker, Wade, Whitaker, Whiteman, and Williams.
    - Dr. H. Claude Hudson, dentist and founder of Broadway Savings and Loan. (Box 34, Folder 12)
      Includes family portraits. See box 31, folder 10.
    - "Early Negro Businesses and Professions" Binder. (Box 34, Folder 13)
      Photographs compiled by Miriam Matthews.
    - African American female doctors. (Box 34, Folder 14)